const Flashcards =[{question: "Latin word of \" Literature\"", 
                    answer: "Litera"},
                    {question: "Refers to the written works of a particular culture, subculture, religion, or philosophy", 
                    answer: "Literature"},
                    {question: "Spoken language that follows natural speech patterns.", 
                    answer: "Prose"},
                    {question: "Made-up stories", 
                    answer: "Fiction Prose"},
                    {question: "Present facts based on truth", 
                    answer: "Non-fictional Prose"},
                    {question: "It is a long, structured narrative that features complex characters and multiple intertwined events", 
                    answer: "Novel"},
                    {question: "It is a brief, focused narrative that centers on a single event, character, or theme", 
                    answer: "Short story"},
                    {question: "It is a short tale that features animal characters",
                    answer: "Fable"},
                    {question: "It is magical story with fantastical elements",
                    answer: "Fairytale"},
                    {question: "It is a traditional tale that explains origins, nature, or culture, often involving gods or supernatural beings",
                    answer: "Myth"},
                    {question: "A story passed down through generations, blending historical facts with fictional elements",
                    answer: "Legend"},
                    {question: "A person\u0060s life story written by someone else",
                    answer: "Biography"},
                    {question: "A person\u0060s life story written by themselves",
                    answer: "Autobiography"},
                    {question: "A personal account focusing on specific memories,",
                    answer: "Memoir"},
                    {question: "A short piece that presents, explains, argues, or reflects on an idea",
                    answer: "Essay"},
                    {question: "A written text intended to be spoken aloud to inform",
                    answer: "Speech"},
                    {question: "It is a creative expression that conveys feelings, typically arranged in lines and stanzas",
                    answer: "Poetry"},
                    {question: "3-line poem with 5-7-5 syllables",
                    answer: "Haiku"},
                    {question: "14-line poem with a specific rhyme scheme",
                    answer: "Sonnet"},
                    {question: "A poem without fixed rhyme or meter",
                    answer: "Free verse"},
                    {question: "A humorous 5-line poem with an AABBA rhyme",
                    answer: "Limerick"},
                    {question: "A narrative poem that tells a story, often meant to be sung",
                    answer: "Ballad"},
                    {question: "It is a form of literature written to be performed by actors",
                    answer: "Drama"},
                    {question: "Serious drama where the main character faces downfall or death",
                    answer: "Tradegy"},
                    {question: "A humorous play with light-hearted events",
                    answer: "Comedy"},
                    {question: "A play where music, songs, and dance help tell the story",
                    answer: "Musical"},
                    {question: "A play based on real historical events or figures",
                    answer: "Historical Drama"},
                    {question: "Broad category that encompasses both literary elements and techniques",
                    answer: "Literary Devices"},
                    {question: "The basic components of storytelling",
                    answer: "Literary Elements"},
                    {question: "Sequence of events that make up a story.",
                    answer: "Plot"},
                    {question: "Part where the setting, characters, and initial situation are introduced.",
                    answer: "Exposition"},
                    {question: "Events that build suspense and develop the central conflict.",
                    answer: "Rising Action"},
                    {question: "Most intense point of the story",
                    answer: "Climax"},
                    {question: "Follow the climax and lead the story toward resolution.",
                    answer: "Falling Action"},
                    {question: "Story\u0060s conclusion, where conflicts are resolved",
                    answer: "Resolution"},
                    {question: "Time and place where a story takes place",
                    answer: "Setting"},
                    {question: "Refers to the people, animals, or beings in a story",
                    answer: "Character"},
                    {question: "Main character in the story",
                    answer: "Protagonist"},
                    {question: "Character or force that opposes the protagonist",
                    answer: "Antagonist"},
                    {question: "A struggle between opposing forcest",
                    answer: "Conflict"},
                    {question: "When a character struggles against another",
                    answer: "Character vs Character"},
                    {question: "Internal conflict, a character struggles with personal doubts",
                    answer: "Character vs Self"},
                    {question: "When a character challenges societal norms",
                    answer: "Character vs Society"},
                    {question: "Lens through which the story is told",
                    answer: "Point Of View(POV)"},
                    {question: "Using pronouns like I, me, my, and our.",
                    answer: "First POV"},
                    {question: "Uses he, she, or they and focuses on one character",
                    answer: "Third Person Limited"},
                    {question: "Narrator knows and describes the thoughts of multiple characters",
                    answer: "Third Person Omniscient"},
                    {question: "Specific methods authors use to convey meaning",
                    answer: "Literary Techniques"},
                    {question: "Uses objects, actions, or events to represent deeper meaning",
                    answer: "Symbolism"},
                    {question: "Direct comparison between two unlike things",
                    answer: "Metaphor"},
                    {question: "Contrast between expectations and reality",
                    answer: "Irony"},
                    {question: "Actual outcome is the opposite of what was expected",
                    answer: "Situational Irony"},
                    {question: "Someone says the opposite of what they mean",
                    answer: "Verbal Irony"},
                    {question: "Uses vivid, sensory language to create strong mental pictures",
                    answer: "Imagery"},
                    {question: "Don Quixote",
                    answer: "Miguel de Cervantes"},
                    {question: "The Necklace",
                    answer: "Guy de Maupassant"},
                    {question: "The Tortoise and the Hare",
                    answer: "AESOP"},
                    {question: "Example of Myth",
                    answer: "The Myth of Prometheus"},
                    {question: "Example of Legends",
                    answer: "King Arthur & The Knights of the Round Table"},
                    {question: "Leonardo da Vinci",
                    answer: "Walter Isaacson"},
                    {question: "The Story of Life",
                    answer: "Helen Keller"},
                    {question: "Educated",
                    answer: "Tara Westover"},
                    {question: "Self-Reliance",
                    answer: "Ralph Waldo Emerson"},
                    {question: "I Have a Dream",
                    answer: "Martin Luther King Jr."},
                    {question: "The Old Pond",
                    answer: "Matsuho Basho"},
                    {question: "Sonnet 18",
                    answer: "William Shakespeare"},
                    {question: "Song of Myself",
                    answer: "Walt Whitman"},
                    {question: "Example of Limerick",
                    answer: "The Adventurous Man from Peru"},
                    {question: "The Rime of the Ancient Mariner",
                    answer: "Samuel Taylor Coleridge"},
                    {question: "Romeo & Juliet",
                    answer: "William Shakespeare"},
                    {question: "The Midsummer Night's Dream",
                    answer: "William Shakespeare"},
                    {question: "The Phantom of the Opera",
                    answer: "Andrew Lloyd Webber"},
                    {question: "The Crucible",
                    answer: "Arthur Miller"},
                    {question: "Refers to the earliest written works created before 500 BCE",
                    answer: "Ancient Literature"},
                    {question: "Practice of passing down stories, values, and knowledge through spoken words",
                    answer: "Oral Tradition"},
                    {question: "Long narrative poems that recount the heroic journeys ",
                    answer: "Epics"},
                    {question: "Feature heroic figures whose actions reflect cultural ideals",
                    answer: "Heroism & Moral Values"},
                    {question: "Explore how fate and the will of gods or supernatural forces often shape human lives",
                    answer: "Fate & Divine Will"},
                    {question: "Reflect on the fragility of life, the inevitability of death, and the desire for legacy or immortality",
                    answer: "Human Condition & Mortality"},
                    {question: "Before 500 BCE",
                    answer: "Ancient Literature"},
                    {question: "500 BCE \u002D 500 CE",
                    answer: "Classical Literature"},
                    {question: "500 \u002D 1500 CE",
                    answer: "Medieval Literature"},
                    {question: "1300 \u002D 1600 CE",
                    answer: "Renaissance Literature"},
                    {question: "1660 \u002D 1800 CE",
                    answer: "Enlightenment and Neoclassical Literature"},
                    {question: "1780 \u002D 1850 CE",
                    answer: "Romanticism"},
                    {question: "1850 \u002D 1910 CE",
                    answer: "Realism & Naturalism"},
                    {question: "1890 \u002D 1945 CE",
                    answer: "Modernism"},
                    {question: "1945 \u002D 1990s CE",
                    answer: "Post Modernism"},
                    {question: "1980s \u002D Present",
                    answer: "Contemporary & Global Literature"}] 

const cardQuestion = document.getElementById("Question");
const cardAnswer = document.getElementById("Answer");
const next = document.getElementById("Next");

next.addEventListener("click", event=>{
    let random = Math.floor(Math.random() * Flashcards.length);

    cardQuestion.textContent = Flashcards[random].question;
    cardAnswer.textContent = Flashcards[random].answer;
    console.log(Flashcards[random].answer);
})